# MARC LLOPART ENAJAS

🧥 Gelida, Barcelona, Spain (Open to relocation) 🜙 +34 633959561 🛮 🗷 llopartdata@gmail.com ☐ LinkedIn Profile ☐ github.com/MarcLlopart ☐ My Portfolio

**SUMMARY** — Data Scientist with a strong background in computational mathematics and data analytics, specializing in machine learning, blockchain technologies, and data visualization.

#### **TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES**

Languages Python, R, SQL, MongoDB, Javascript, Bash, Solidity, Git Cloud AWS, Azure

Web3 Analytics Dune, Nansen, Defillama, Artemis **Libraries** Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Statsmodel,

Matplotlib, Streamlit OS Debian, Ubuntu, MacOS, Windows

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Algorand Foundation** Jul 2024 - Present

Data Analyst Remote

- Conducted an in-depth correlation analysis to identify key factors influencing crypto market capitalization, providing actionable insights for strategic decision-making..

 Designed and implemented multiple interactive dashboards to monitor asset inflows and outflows on centralized exchanges (CEXs) and track the adoption trends of Liquid Staking Tokens.

Collaborated with cross functional teams to provide any statistic needed, from ecosystem to engineering questions.

**Banco Sabadell** Dec 2023 - Jul 2024

Data Scientist (Economic Capital & ICAAP)

Sant Cugat del Vallés, Barcelona (Hybrid)

- Developed and implemented models to assess and quantify operational risks, non-performing credit, climatic risk, and sectorial concentration.

Conducted thorough data analysis to identify patterns, trends, and anomalies impacting the bank's risk exposure.

- Partnered with cross-functional teams, delivering data-driven insights to support diverse needs, from ecosystem analysis to technical engineering inquiries.

**Perpetuum Progress** Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

Web3 Researcher & Developer

Remote

- Researched B2B payment methods for Web3 Data Exchange focused on the Mobility Industry.
- Implemented a Private Blockchain network based on Proof of Authority (PoA).
- Integrated Cross-Chain functionalities in a private blockchain.

Aily Labs Jul 2023 - Sep 2023

Data Scientist Internship

Barcelona, Spain (Hybrid)

- Developed a Recommender Engine from implicit feedback to enhance user retention on internal App.
- Created tables and views using SQL and Python.
- Coded new OOP classes and functions to process data and develop scalable features.

## Freelancer - Clash Royale League

May 2021 - May 2022

Data Scientist

Remote

Remote

- Prepared data from players using Excel to assist in deck choices.
- Delivered reports with key strategies for games based on data analysis.
- Improved player performance and consistency, achieving Top 6 in the World Finals.

Jul 2018 - Dec 2020 Data Analyst

**SK Gaming** 

- Delivered reports for match strategies based on previous data studies.

- Prepared competition data using Excel and Google Studio and assisted in team strategy development.
- Scouted new players during off-season periods to enhance team performance.
- Achievements include Top 2 in the 2020 World Finals.

### **EDUCATION**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

Master's Degree in Blockchain Technologies

Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

Bachelor of Science in Computational Mathematics and Data Analytics Thesis Title: Developing a Payment Method for a Web3 Mobility Data Space

**NOVA School of Science & Technology** 

Semester Abroad Erasmus+ Program Program: Data Science and Big Data

Languages

English - Advanced

Spanish - NativeCatalan - Native

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

Barcelona

2019-2023

Barcelona

2022-2023

Lisbon, Portugal